bargaintown.ie 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy

**INTRODUCTION** ****

At Bargaintown Limited, we are committed to respecting the privacy and security of all users and visitors to www.bargaintown.ie. This policy sets out the basis for which information collected about you by Bargaintown Limited.

By submitting your information and using our Website, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by us in the manner set out in this privacy policy.

This policy sets out how information about you is collected and used by Bargaintown Limited strictly in accordance with all current data protection laws, including the EU2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011.

For the purpose of the EU2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the data controller is Bargaintown Limited, 8-10 Slaney Road, Dublin Industrial Estate, Glasnevin, Dublin 11. For any privacy queries please contact GDPR@bargaintown.ie

The personal data you share with us will only be used for the specified purposes documented below and will never be shared with any third party.

From time to time this Privacy and [Cookie Policy](http://www.bargaintown.ie/cookies) may change. We recommend that you check this page each time your visit or submit personal information to Bargaintown Limited.

**TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**

**Personal Data**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * Identity Data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier.
  * Contact Data includes billing address, shipping address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * Financial Data includes payment card details and, where you or your business have or apply for a credit account with us, bank account details and information held by credit reference and fraud prevention agencies.
  * Transaction Data includes details about your trading history.
  * Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website/or any apps.
  * Profile Data includes your username and password, products/services provided to you, feedback and survey responses.
  * Usage Data includes information as to how you use our website.
  * Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences as to whether you are happy to receive marketing from us and, if so, your communication preferences.

**Non-Personal Data**

Non-Personal Data is information that cannot be used to identify or contact you. This is statistical and analytical data about our users browsing actions and patterns.

**WHY WE COLLECT THE DATA**

**Why we collect Personal Data**

-          To provide you with goods and services you have ordered.

-          To contact you regarding your order.

-          To respond to communications.

-          To enter competitions.

-          To complete research surveys.

-          To inform you of promotions/events.

**Why we collect Non-Personal Data**

-          Gain a better understanding of our website users site usage so that we can use this information to improve the website and provide our users with an enhanced customer experience

-          Estimate audience size and usage patterns

-          Store user preferences so you can customise the site

-          To track return visitors

**HOW WE COLLECT DATA**

**Online**

**Personal Data**

When customers use our website, there are 4 instances where we collect personal data.

  1. Registering on the website
  2. Placing an order
  3. Making a payment
  4. Making an enquiry

Registering on the website

When you register with the website, we create an account for you. We collect the following data so that you can select them quickly any time you wish to place an order:

-          Email address

-          First and last name

-          Address

-          Mobile phone number

-          Password

This data is stored on Magico servers, who are our eCommerce platform providers.

Placing an order

When you place an order on our website, if you are not registered already, we collect the following information that’s required to complete the order:

-          Email address

-          First and last name

-          Address

-          Mobile phone number

This data is stored on Magico’s servers, and sent to us by email.

Making a payment

Our website uses Realex Payments for taking credit card payments. We don’t store your credit card information in our database, the data is passed on directly to Realex. More information about Realex can be found at https://www.realexpayments.com

The details that are requested are Card type, Card expiry, Card Number, and security code (CVV or CVC)

Enquiries

We have a contact form on our website, for customers to send us questions or enquiries.

-          Name

-          Email address

-          Telephone number

-          Message

This data is stored on Magico servers. It is also emailed to us, so is stored on Microsoft 365 email servers.

**Non-personal Data**

We record all activity on our website using Google analytics. This data comprises of what pages within our website you visit, how long you spend there, and what link sent you to the page. It is non-personal and cannot be used to identify you or contact you. Please refer to Google Analytics https://www.google.com/analytics for more information.

**In-store**

**Personal Data**

In store, we will only record data given by the customer directly relating to placing an order, or our measuring service. The details asked for will be:

-          Name

-          Address

-          Phone number

-          Email address (where email receipt requested)

This data will be securely stored in our point of sales system, and will not be shared with any 3rd parties for sales or marketing purposes.

Our stores are all CCTV monitored. This is recorded for security. It is used exclusively for the following:

-          To prevent fraud

-          For the greater security of our customers and staff

-          To prevent and detect crime.

We store our footage securely and it will never be shared with 3rd parties, with exception for law enforcement in terms of detecting crime.

**Non-personal Data**

We do not record any non-personal data in store.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please see below to find out more about these rights: 

  * _Request access to your personal data_.
  * _Request correction of your personal data_.
  * _Request erasure of your personal data_.
  * _Object to processing of your personal data_.
  * _Request restriction of processing your personal data_.
  * _Request transfer of your personal data_.
  * _Right to withdraw consent_.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us _._

_Bargaintown Limited_

_8-10 Slaney Road_

_Dublin Industrial Estate_

_Glasnevin_

_Dublin 11  
_

You have the right to:  __

  * **Request access  **to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it. 

  * **Request correction  **of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us. 

  * **Request erasure  **of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

  * **Object to processing  **of your personal data where we are relying on our legitimate interest (or that of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms. 

  * **Request restriction of processing  **of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following situations: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

  * **Request the transfer  **of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 

  * **Withdraw consent at any time  **where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

**CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to make any changes to the Privacy Policy which will be effective when posted on our website <http://www.bargaintown.ie/page/privacy-policy/180>

**CONTACT US**

Any questions, comments or queries regarding this Privacy Statement should be addressed to GDPR Team, and can be made by post, email or phone

Post:  
GDPR Team   
Units 8-10 Slaney Road  
Dublin Industrial Estate  
Glasnevin  
Dublin  
D11E285

Email:  

Phone:  
01 – 671 3158

Privacy notice for job applicants
